In this tutorial video, we use the 11th version of Doshi Marvelous Designer.
If you need to learn the 10th version of Marvelous Designer, please watch the previous video.
In order to make it easier to learn, the Doshi Marvelous Designer is used in this tutorial.
We have learned how to create clothing in Marvelous Designer through previous tutorials.
Now we will learn how to make your clothes look more real.
You can use default fabric without modifying the fabric.
By modifying the fabric properties, you can make your clothes look more real.
Before starting, open the 3D window to show the thickness of the fabric and the texture of the fabric.
Please note that default fabric is 0.5mm thick.
Now let's apply the fabric to the clothes.
Click on the Add button of the fabric window to add a new fabric.
Double-click on the name to modify.
Select the adjustment panel tool, then press the Shift button to select all the thick and shawl panels.
Click on the application button next to the fabric.
Apply the fabric of the newly created.
When selecting a fabric, the outline of the panel with this fabric will be displayed as orange.
Select the new fabric of the T-shirt.
You can adjust its properties in the property editor below.
At the bottom of the property editor is the physical property.
You can change the physical properties of the fabric in it, or select the default fabric provided by Marvelous Designer.
When you select a preset fabric, the physical properties below will follow the selection and produce a change.
You can also adjust these values according to the need for manual adjustment.
Here we select the preset fabric, which is Knit Pick Jersey.
Select it and start the simulation.
Please refer to other physical properties teaching videos for detailed explanations on physical properties.
After changing the physical properties, you can manually organize the panels.
Next, let's take a look at the material settings.
First, you can choose a different preset type.
In addition, you can add the material pattern to the fabric texture.
Or set the strength of the hair line or change the pattern for the fabric.
Click on the color block to change the material color.
About transparency, the lower its value, the lighter the fabric, the more translucent it can be.
Please note that the high-quality rendering option in the 3D window of the hook selection can be selected.
It is better to check the material material effect.
However, as a T-shirt, it is still not transparent.
These preset fabrics can also be imported into the library.
Let's try to apply preset fabric to the pocket.
First, add a new fabric to the fabric window.
Select a new fabric.
Select the adjustment panel tool and click on the pocket.
Then click on the application button next to the new fabric and apply it to the panel.
Then open the Fabric folder in the Library window.
Here you can preview the reference effects of various fabrics and drag them onto the fabric to apply these properties.
In this video, we will use lightweight denim so that you can easily distinguish the materials.
When dragging the fabric to the newly created fabric, you will see that the name of the fabric has changed.
Double-click to change it.
The fabric dragged in from the Library window will also contain materials and physical properties.
You can modify other properties in the property editor.
Now we will change the material type of the fabric to Fabric Shiny.
Can you feel the difference?
Click on the control button to start the simulation.
After modifying the material physical properties, the wearing effect of the clothing will change.
Because the physical properties will affect the stretch of the clothing, the wrinkle texture, etc.
Therefore, modifying the appropriate physical properties will help the clothing look more real.
Therefore, after changing the material physical properties, you can adjust the 2D version according to the effect in the 3D window.
Please save your work as a project file and it will be used in the following courses.